turn off your cell phone guessing
Michael
relax your lips relax the corners of
your mouth maybe little smile relax your
forehead
pull in your stomach slightly
relax your eyelids
relax your fingers
and then slowly come to breath count 10
long slow exhale
askew la Mer to come sit with you
their bodies fragrant you can even with
your eyes closed you can smell the
fragrance of their orality
see how beautiful they are
and appreciate one thing about them
that's a mental prostration
then think about something you did nice
yesterday and that you'd like to offer
to them little breakthrough that your
head
be specific something nice you did
yesterday or a sweet idea you had
then admit to them something you did
yesterday which was not so nice old bad
habit old bad thought be honest whenever
you do it again we tell them in your
mind at least tell them in your mind and
that will help you stop
and ask them to teach you keep teaching
you even if you're not so were they
sometimes
I sent this day in your life and your
future lies
then put your mind on how many years of
life you guess you might have left put a
number on it make it up ten years maybe
I have 15 years maybe 20 try to imagine
how many years you have
so let's say it's 20 years and I guess
about a third of that is spent sleeping
a third or a quarter is spent sleeping
so it's down to 15 years now
15 years um a wig
then thus 15 years about maybe two hours
a day is spent cooking and eating if I
take out the cooking time take out about
fifteen percent I have maybe twelve
years left
grocery time buying groceries taking
showers
so maybe 11 years not
then just working to pay my rent working
to pay for my food maybe eight years
left
and I have obligations to my family I
have to spend time with parents and
other family otherwise I'm not a good
person I have to spend some time with
them six years left
my friends need some time just time to
talk to people I can't be alone all the
time I have to to have friends I have to
pay attention to the Friends app to see
them once in a while talk to them for
years left
I enjoy some things online I I send some
emails keep in touch check what's
happening with other people we chat
facebook about two years left in my life
for the whole rest of my life real-time
free to practice clear time to meditate
to see hemp teenis I have about two
years that's all
so hard to fight to find a few blocks up
time spaces of time half an hour 20
minutes so hard in the whole day to find
free time to meditate keep my book study
so little time
let's do here for a few minutes
then please take three deep breaths
three deep breath
and you can sell it open your eyes take
a stretch nice meditation very quiet
thank you really nice nice group
meditators
purgator she met dawn dawn rerunning she
and egg empire
he sang gation to maintain
yee chinn i show you know and i'll come
here
me too don coqui janana time to buy did
that they can sue G nagi-chan
he pays a monkey no not pinches some get
to perch on Toronto ki toh na na charger
baidu the naked sushi nage jr e bisogna
ye la pincha some gare de parfum toronto
key to nama time to do
that Nick out some tea nagi-chan yet
gave his son honky I can share some gare
du by Joe Kagan
so I'll give you a paper maybe tomorrow
with the nine the nine death the reasons
for death meditation okay we weren't
supposed to go this far but you guys are
fast so I'll just review them with you
right now so there are three basic
principles the first one is it's certain
that you have to die okay and there are
three reasons for that first one is the
traditional text says chittagong chicken
congee young doctor mehbeh the Lord of
Death will definitely come and there's
nothing that can stop him at that time
okay it doesn't matter how strong you
are or what kind of medicines you use or
where you go okay second reason why
death is certain is sailor number
matching DJ permit a puddle jumper you
can't add any time to your life and
you're constantly losing that the time
the time is dropping every hour that's
the second reason third reason Sunday
say aren't you Joey long mappa we just
did that one what's that even in the
time you have love you don't have time
to practice okay you're just so busy you
know to get a few hours of retreat here
you know it's millions of dollars and
people are working for months and you
also have to come from far away
out of work a lot of trouble okay and I
don't know in the yogic theory of
digestion you eat like a doughnut and
then it goes down your throat and the
stomach process is it takes out the junk
and and by the time you get to the
essence of a doughnut it's like one drop
of nutrition you know maybe then your
your practice time is like that to get
one hour of practice takes like a
hundred hours of life you know so even
in the time you have left the time you
have to practice is very it's very small
okay which means if you get a chance to
practice take it okay you're in the
airport we always do yoga in the airport
we found out the cure for jet lag is due
to yoga's in the airport one when you
leave and one when you get there you
know and okay so when you see a moment
take it somebody asked me how did you
have time to finish the epidemic Rocha
took me 12 years I said it was all in
dentist's office waiting for Rinpoche
you know I did it all in the dentist
office waiting for rim patina he had
like 50 bad teeth okay
yeah okay all right second basic
principle is what yeah you don't know
when it's going to come you know it's
going to come but you don't know when
okay and there are three reasons for
that we call them reason number four
reason number five reason number six
because they're going to be nine total
okay first one is cheers on bling way
say long yeppa Mempa in this realm where
we live there's no fixed lifetime we
can't you don't get a guarantee when
you're born okay that's the fourth
reason fifth reason chicken munching
soon can you mwah the things that can
kill you are many the things that can
keep you alive are very few sometimes I
think the world must be a tantric
Mandela because there's not enough room
to grow all the spinach I have to eat
like now I mean if I eat like so much
spinach in a green drink and Rihanna
makes me green to make any money if I if
I have that much spinach there should be
miles and miles of spinach fields but
there's not you know there's very little
place in the planet to grow spinach in
most places you can't grow it right so
the things that but the things I can
kill you are everywhere okay all right
now we're on reason number six we're
going to start recent number six okay
reason number six which is the third
reason why we don't know when we're
going to die okay is Lucien dunam 21 the
body is fragile okay the body is fragile
I love I don't know about you you're not
old enough but when I was a kid it was
really cool to have a 19 55 Chevy all
right you know those big boxy Chevrolet
you know what she's real fun full
we had songs about them and you know
those cars are how old are they known 60
years old something they're like 60
years of dirty they're younger than me
and they're all fell apart all the 55
Chevys in the world fell apart they're
made of metal I made a bone and skin you
know it's hard to find a 55 Chevy that's
still right it's hard to find I bought
one a while back I sold it shortly
afterwards they're just always falling
apart I had to put oil in it every 10
mile the brakes don't work in those days
and nothing works anyway but your body
still goes you know okay let's talk
about that one mmm get you ready Adam
q10 Simba okay no problem you can look
for lus shi Yan Lucien lus SI je n
little bit she has a real coffee okay
guten symbol Lucien din yung Chen Yong
Nam geelong yep remember me life is when
you're going to die is not certain
because of the third reason which is
that the body is so fragile okay nam
chua means fragile okay in colloquial
tibetan yumcha means was patella
dictionary and yum yum and yum cha a few
choom choom choom means a shy or you
know like like that you know Kishida
young children means he's really shy or
he's kind of what he called like bashful
yeah that's great bashful am too but
here it means fragile the body is
fragile chinden mhmm very fragile
theatre chicken monkey so again Yong
Yong even though it's true that the
things that can kill you are many and
the things that can keep your lab or a
few wrong chuckling dude the sashing
check by Shekinah if our body was like
what that guy's it's not transformers
what's a guy the big one the nice one
Optimus Prime Optimus Prime if we had a
body like Optimus Prime it would be okay
you know okay like if there were lots of
things that could kill us if the roof
fell on us would be like bush you know
if we had an optimist prime transformer
body it would be okay that there are
many dangerous things around us but but
she can't munching me can you Denis too
boo boo it chewy bullet are okay but our
body is like a bubble like a water
bubble you know in your bathtub little
bubble our bodies like that Sarah mrs.
but some kick young chiba if you get
stuck by a cactus thorn
and you're not lucky it can kill you
okay it can kill you I think Abraham
Lincoln's son was killed by a thorn he
just got stuck by a thorn he got an
infection and he died okay mama Belma in
the first three-year retreat she got she
fell into a cactus and and she had her
hand was swollen for three years you
know it never cured okay it can kill you
just one little thing can kill you so
our body is not like Optimus Prime
chicken my blood Sam I super Tom kichi
was soaked in Jimbo me Cooper it doesn't
take much to kill a human body a few
germs you can get them anywhere okay you
can get them what's that nice restaurant
at the top of their casino in Singapore
some French restaurant I lost a month's
salary dinner anyway in that restaurant
you can get a what do you call it
salmonella I could kill you okay many
people died that way okay in the nicest
restaurant in Singapore okay subtext
shaky and can be pente even if our body
was like Optimus Prime check by tech
means by the way like armored or check
bombings super what do you call it this
solid let me check by okay repented
lay because the says
was shooting the letter to a
friend okay shaman's friend ting like
Gachet and ting me mitra kalyana mitra
and ting means letter okay
siddhanth on Bogut Owney Madden borrow a
sickbed agenda daka tell a young in uber
manana shin dunya mamita maritza Sodom
saw means the surface of this planet the
earth okay limbo means the Great
mountains of the earth like Mount
Everest and the gatos the great oceans
of the earth pacific ocean atlantic
ocean indian ocean okay there will come
a time according to Abby Dharma third
chapter when the Sun will supernova okay
and and that's normal all all stars
supernovae eventually so in the
abhidhamma they say this-this-this star
that we call the Sun it's burning right
it's a reaction and then and then it
will start to fail just before it fails
it will in in the AA bhi darna it says
nima doon it means it will get seven
hundred percent more powerful the light
of the Sun will increase by seven
hundred percent suddenly supernova and
then it gets too bloody caught well
eventually it's a black hole you know
first it brings out for a while okay so
when the time of the seven sons they
call it the days of the seventh sense
okay when when our Sun explodes barwa
the earth will catch first it's very
easy sad it's like first all the trees
start to dry out and then they catch on
fire the people died early and then the
oceans dry out and then the mountains
melt okay and then the earth melts and
in the earth dissolves and then the
Earth evaporates and then it's just
nothing dust goes back to death okay
borrow a sec volute indeed young if even
Mount Everest is going to melt and
become TOA young a looper this lupa
means to be left over okay it doesn't
mean buddy okay dupa means even if the
tower is not left telemon's dust if you
crush Mount Everest into dust and then
even the dust will evaporate okay tell a
minger dopamine gear there'll be nothing
left shin dunya mamita then this fragile
body which itself who needs to mention
this fragile body okay where will you
buy you have an Optimus Prime body then
it doesn't help even if your body was
armored or something all all things on
this planet will dissolve everything
oceans mountains then your body come on
he's like come on mirchi so much its
armies who needs to mention come on you
know okay then he has another quotation
it's from the same book sending your
monologue etapa de chile chip away can
meet Anna look Jon eKEY local a second
con la Danny Mozart a Sadie near
monogatari a life is full of danger long
geeta bali chipper Chipper our life is
our body is like a bubble that's blown
in the wind like those kids play with
those bubble things and then they start
to float and how long do they last okay
changeup again Madonna we are more
impermanent than done okay look Jim look
you guys know Oh glue up John right so
yeah move means to breath bathe in and
up Jim means to breathe out okay OOP oke
oke means brass say okay I want you to
sound like a monkey Oh
oh yeah good okay then in the RV Dahmer
there's a meditation preparation called
oak joonam okay it means exhale inhale
exhale inhale okay then countries like
Burma and Sri Lanka and Thailand the
only Buddhism that reached there with
the abhidhamma the the Maji mica didn't
middleway didn't go there emptiness
didn't go there mind only didn't go
there China got mind only China got
middle way but the southern countries
sri lanka Burma and Thailand they just
gotta be Dharma and vinaya out of the
five Great subjects they only got those
two and so breathing meditation became a
big thing in the southern countries and
then there are systems like vipassana
meditation which I I learned it was the
first meditation I learned hundred years
ago all they do is watch their breath
okay then that's not enough okay it's
it's not enough it's a good thing it's a
good preparation but it's like warming
up instead of running the Olympics okay
like you don't practice your whole life
and go to the Olympics and warm up and
watch the other people race okay you
race ok so that's just a warm-up ok oak
do love is just a warm-up but it's a
good warm-up but it shouldn't be the
only thing you do ok oak do love means
watch your to breathe in it here it
means breathe in and out Nicky law
ballet after you have fallen asleep say
calm this cipa say that generally means
to kill all right but without the pole
or without the coal it means to wake up
ok from sleep so be careful when you
gently ok it means that to wake from
sleep seiko means to have time to have
the up the leisure to wake from your
sleep north side chain
yeah it's an unbelievable the fact that
you wake up in the morning is one before
i went to shivananda center in bahamas
they had a nice rabbi talking jewish
rabbi his old and he was very cool and
somebody said why are you so happy he
said I woke up this morning you know I
didn't die in my sleep he was so happy
he's like 19 I'm like why are you always
so happy since I didn't die this more
ice I woke up again so here in the
the gardener says the same
thing okay the fact that you woke up
this morning is a miracle notes aren't
you okay that your breath is still going
you know who makes your breath go
scientists are you know all the doctors
all the research guys billions of
dollars to figure out why do people
breathe what triggered it you know what
made the first breath we understand
karma right if you have the Karma you
will breed you know you'll be the only
person on the Titanic to survive if you
have the Karma nothing can kill you
iceberg cannot kill you you know if you
don't have a karma to breathe then you
get stuck by one cactus you would die ok
we understand ok scientists are doctors
are like why what causes the first
breath to start ok then he gives a nice
explanation of this quotation ok my
clock just told me it's Sunday it's
Easter tomorrow ok share Romney log
backup Oh grappa junam do when you fall
asleep the gross breath withdraws
pratyahara it comes into the body ok do
they do motor maloom now look at you a
much hipper but Joe or trauma means the
subtle elements of the body ok the the
subtle wind element still passes in and
out of your body ok so you
sleep but with a very reduced breathing
unless your husband snores and that's a
lot stronger than normal really but most
people there just barely alive while
they're asleep the breath is just barely
moving okay it shift to a different
level of the element of air okay much
hipper jus wanna rob a monkey OOP to
loop dupa sanely then for that will you
call it suspended gross breath to
reactivate when you wake up notes Archie
it's unbelievable okay if that you don't
die because the the suspended gross
breath for it to reawaken in the morning
it's like a miracle okay it shouldn't it
doesn't have to you can just die you can
just stop breathing in the morning okay
but the fact that you keep breathing
it's a miracle okay that you wake up and
start breathing again ruff ruff
breathing gross breathing it's a miracle
Dane unobtainium made this summer sergej
kadar Oh Ronnie na naman chow mein Nina
I like this I always think about this I
don't know why when r imitate taught
this it really struck me if it's not
sure when you're gonna die okay so the
situation is this you're sitting in your
house okay you're you're sitting in your
what do you call it yurt you're trying
to meditate you know and then somebody
sends you a message in your food box it
says someone's coming to kill you in the
next 24 hours good luck okay somebody's
coming to kill you in your urine in the
next 24 hours good luck and then you
like check the back there's nothing on
the back you know
then you know you would do something to
get the house ready you know there was a
movie called straw dogs yeah this nerd
puts bear traps and you know he he makes
sure the water is gonna fall on the guy
you know he fixes the housetop with all
these traps because somebody's going to
come to kill him you know still if you
know someone's going to kill you you
would you wouldn't wait until tomorrow
you see what I mean maybe they won't
come tonight oh I'll wait till tomorrow
to get ready you know I'll find all the
knives in the house tomorrow you know
that would be kind of stupid the minute
you get the note put the note down look
in the house for knives or sharp spoons
or anything okay okay do something now
don't hang out don't say oh maybe they
won't come today maybe it'll be tomorrow
morning okay okay chaining they dumped
us so glad Samba you have to do
something now you get a message like
that somebody says they're coming but
I'm not telling you when they're coming
then you should rather get ready first
and relaxed later okay dopa so let's
umber Tata run church in young are
you sure Jake Bouma you so you should
practice do your practice you know if
you have to skip something today you
know skip your we chat and do some death
meditation okay and then you can do it
if you don't die in the morning you can
do we chat in the afternoon okay it's
more logical do you practice first to
carry your practice first then do all
your reach out stuff in the afternoon if
you do die you did the right thing ok if
you don't die you can still do each
other okay Tyler son puts on the leg
ajooba but our habit is to say I'm
working on a project
I've got a client you know I'm writing a
book so I'm just going to schedule it
this way I will finish the book first
and then I'll practice that i'll do the
death meditations after that ok it
should be the opposite ok do your death
meditations first if you die everything
is taken care of finish the book later
ok if you don't die you can finish the
book it doesn't matter you didn't lose
anything better to prioritize do your
meditation first in the morning get the
yoga out of the way what's the
definition of yoga that which prevents
me from eating breakfast that which
stands between me and my waffles it's
different definition of yoga ok so get
it get it finished get all your practice
done in the morning then if you die
you're safe if you don't die you can do
your other stuff later it makes sense ok
yeah but they seem legit John Anthony
run Kieran Cooper unity but if you do
your we chat first and you think you're
going to do your meditation later run
lupa you are cheating yourself ok you
are cheating yourself nobody's cheating
you you're cheating yourself ok how late
this class go Scott 10-15 ok I'll take a
break shortly we're going to take a
little pee pee break j guangdong bay
let's finish this one it will take a
little break low low dawid isla de nan
ki Lee Jae Suk 22 Cheney large sandwich
Russia Janey ampa d Tom Cholewa punk day
he says if you want to meet a demon you
know there's a big debate in America
does a double exists a hundred years ago
everybody believed in the devil now
there's very few people
the demo and there's a book that says
the devil's greatest achievement in the
last hundred years was to make everybody
not believe in him anyway there do exist
Devils there do exist demons okay and he
he describes one okay but by the way in
general they exist if you meditate a lot
you can meet one you can you can
recognize them okay it's scary it's
really there they exist okay that's
another subject okay o Lord awadallah
Dean Duncan legal jujitsu so I'm so busy
I have a plan I'm gonna do a really good
retreat next year and I'm gonna start my
book next month I'm just busy right now
I got a few things to finish up and then
I'm gonna really start my six-times book
again okay and and do all my debt death
meditation so I'm going to come to
Diamond Mountain Dew one month or treat
solo solo retreat by myself I think I'm
definitely 2017 I just got a few things
to finish up in 2016 and then I'll take
care of that okay there's somebody
coming to kill you in your yard in the
next 24 hours it's better to look for
the sharp spoons now ok ok do your dust
minute d retreat now take care of your
meditation do your yoga practice then if
you don't die you can do your other
stuff ok if you do die you're ready ok
like a daughter or a son returning to
their parents home you're ready you're
you're already oh you're gonna die okay
I'm all packed up what time are we
leaving ok like that there's no fear if
you if you got ready there's this weird
thing then you're like okay I'm ready ok
let's go ok i'm already ok so he says j
guangdong but google tumba says if you
want to meet a real demon it's that idea
that I will wait till later okay I just
got a few things to take care of and
then I'm definitely going to get more
serious about my practice okay okay that
said it's it's you're cheating yourself
you're when he caught you're deceiving
yourself okay okay one more okay for
this one you have to understand
something I spent 25 years living with
my teacher one of the strangest things I
had to that he used to do he would be
watching the news on TV he'd say I could
come up and watch the news and he had a
tweezers and he'd be going because
Tibetans don't have beards okay they're
so lucky like Americans we have to shave
every day just got looks like he's been
in a war every money
Tibetans they're like okay they're so
lucky one day I was in the debate ground
you know you're all stuff together and
then some guys going like this he's
going like this I'm like what are you
doing man he said I said there's a
debate going on you know he said yeah
but I never saw anybody with hair on
okay not saying they got done the jokes
inning so we think I'll do my practice I
try to finish this after I finish this
thing I have to do then the same llama
gunton konjo timbira may said later
Megan Carr potion chicken chicken
jmontie the stuff you still have to
finish the projects you didn't quite
finish are like an old man's hair beard
because what happens as you get older
they grow back faster those of you who
have hair in your ears you know this or
mean like you pull it out the next
morning is like Bing then you just give
up I can forget so old man's hair grows
really fast you pull it out and it's
like being comes back okay okay Jacon
Jacon means you cut it you keep cutting
cutting kin means present participle you
cut you cut you cut and it just keeps
going back faster okay what's he talking
about stuff you have to do before you
could do your practice okay it's like
old man hair okay it just Boop comes
back more another pressing and then
another project and in another pen thing
and one more thing you have to do okay
it just keeps growing okay
all right we're going to take a pee-pee
break there especially me and then come
back in like 10-15 minutes okay okay